愿我的仁慈  胜过
"My mercy...prevails...
我的怒火
over my wrath."
杰瑞
Jerry!
好啊  朱迪斯
S'up, Jude?!
瑞克
Hey, Rick.
一切还好吗
Everything okay?
我只是来吃你们做的灰胡桃煎锅蛋糕的
Just came for some of that butternut skillet cake you guys make.
你从神之国远道而来就为了吃甜点吗
You rode out from the Kingdom for dessert?
没错
Hells yah.
结果你被拉来砌墙了
You got roped into masonry duty.
西迪克
Siddiq, man.
没法拒绝他
Dude's impossible to say no to.
我继续干活了
Back to it.
你快走
Just go!
你不用这样做
You don't have to do this.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
先躲这里  等我和我爸爸谈
It's just ‭'til I can talk to my dad.
如果他还不回来  我们就去找他
If he's not back soon, we'll meet him there.
希望他们会和他在一起
Hopefully, they'll be with him.
米琼恩呢
What about Michonne?
我得亲眼去看
抱歉我没有先道别  我很快回来
米琼恩
爸爸
伊妮德
你看见了吗
You seeing this?
北边收到  有枪声
North copies. Got shots here.
西边也是  他们在干什么
West, too. What are they doing?
行尸还没杀完  他们就会用光弹药
They'll run outta ammo before they run outta walkers.
我看到了
I got eyes on it.
南边结束通话
South out.
他们想开一条路
They're trying to make a path.
用尸体挡住行尸
Blocking out the walkers with bodies.
他们要出来了
They're gonna get out.
我们得告诉所有人
Man, we need to tell everybody --
南边遭到攻击
South down!
出去  大家都出去
Get out! Everybody, get out now!
喂  喂
Hey! Hey!
《行尸走肉》
我看见了
I see it.
我的线把它绊倒了  我来
It got tripped up on my wire. I got it.
小屋就在前面  在林木线之外
The cottage is just ahead, out of the tree-line.
有熟铁围栏
It's got a wrought-iron fence.
屋里有食物和水
There's food and water inside.
救世军不知道那里
The Saviors don't know about it.
在我带回以西结之前  你们在那很安全
You'll be safe there until I make it back with Ezekiel.
你一个人对付他们所有人吗
You versus all of them?
是啊
Yeah.
他们毫无胜算
They don't stand a chance.
要去的不止是卡萝尔
It's not just Carol.
还有我
I'm going, too.
不行
No. You're not.
他们杀了我哥哥
They killed my brother.
我不会让他们也杀了你
And I'm not gonna let 'em kill you.
我可以的
I can do it.
我可以帮你
I can help you.
摩根教我用棍
Morgan taught me the stick.
你教我用枪
You taught me the gun.
不行
It's not happening.
走吧
Come on.
我不...
I-I don't...
爸爸
Dad.
-怎么回事  -爸爸
- How... ‭- Dad...
没事
...it's all right.
会没事的
It's gotta be.
我之前不确定你能否及时赶回来
I wasn't sure if you'd make it back before...
但为了以防万一
But just in case, you know...
我想确保我跟你道别
...I wanted to make sure I was able to say goodbye.
不  是他们干的
No. It's them. It's them.
他们不...
They -- They don't --
不是...
It wasn't...
卡尔
Carl.
不
No.
-不  -我被咬了
- No. - ‭I got bit.
我在带人回来
I was bringing someone back.
他叫西迪克
His name's Siddiq.
我们之前在加油站见过他
We saw him at that gas station, before...
不是救世军干的
It wasn't the Saviors.
事情只是发生了
It just happened.
我被咬了
I got bit.
尼根现在要杀了你
Negan's gonna kill you now.
我说  他要杀了你
I said he's gonna kill you.
而我无法阻止
And there's nothing I can do to stop that.
你听见我说话了吗
Hey. You hear me?
我让我的人获得了自由
I ferried my people to freedom.
我会怎样并不重要
What befalls me now matters not.
不  那很重要  笨蛋
No. It matters, idiot.
我喜欢你  以西结
I liked you, Ezekiel.
你懂的
You got it.
你懂你没法做得更好
You got that you couldn't do better than you had it.
你接受了现实
You accepted things for what they were,
你没什么奇思异想
and you didn't get any big ideas in your head.
然后瑞克来了  让你有了鬼点子
And then Rick went ‭and planted one right in there.
结果就成了这样
And here we are.
事情越来越糟糕
Shit's getting shittier.
而你要死了
And you're gonna die.
我做了一个能让我安心的选择
I made a choice I could live with.
现在轮到你做了
Now it's your turn to do the same.
亨利
Henry!
他们没有足够人手守卫所有围墙
‭They don't have enough people to guard all the walls.
是的  但他们的确有人手
No, but they do have people.
-以西结也在他们手上  -我看见了
- And they have Ezekiel. - I saw him.
他被关在这里的另一边
They got him on the other side of this place.
我们能干掉他们
We can take them.
一个接一个
One by one.
不  如果我们攻击一个
No, if we hit one of them,
其他人都可能发现
that could call them all.
最好避开他们  直到无法避开
It's better just to avoid them until we can't.
亨利
Henry.
他也在这里
He's here, too.
在哪
Where?
你看见他了吗  他们抓到他了吗
Did you see him? Do they have him?
是啊  我看见他往这边跑  然后不见了
Yeah, I saw him run this way, and then he was gone.
但他会躲起来的
But he'll hide.
他不会跟他们短兵相接
He won't take them on face-to-face.
我们得现在行动
We have to do this now.
如果不得不干掉他们  就下手
So if we have to take them, we take them.
这样好些吗
Is that better?
是的
Yeah...
谢谢
Thanks.
我带了这些
I, um, I got these.
是非处方非类固醇抗炎药
They're over-the-counter, non-steroidal anti-inflammatories.
这能帮助退烧
They'll, um -- they'll help a little with the fever.
对我爸妈就有效
They did for my mom and dad.
求你拿去吧
Please take them.
你儿子
Your son...
他该吃这些药
he should have them.
你是医生吗
You're a doctor?
我之前是住院医生
I was a resident... before.
嗯
Yeah.
你叫西迪克
Your name is Siddiq?
是的
Yes.
你知道他是医生吗
Did you know he was a doctor?
这是你带他回来的原因吗
Is that why you brought him back?
他一个人活不下去
He wasn't gonna make it alone.
他需要我们
He needed us.
这就是原因
That's why.
他是加油站那个人
He was the one at the gas station.
水  给他喝水
Water. Give him water.
慢点  好吗
Easy. You got it?
慢点  慢点
Slowly, slowly.
停下
Make it stop.
让他们停下
Make them stop.
-我做不到  -你可以
- I can't. - ‭You can.
你是他们的一员
You're one of them.
他们会听你的
They'll listen to you.
求你了
Please.
你说过山顶寨是安全的  对吧
You said that Hilltop's safe, right?
没错
Yeah.
我们得把大家带到那里去
We need to get everybody there.
我们可以把卡尔带过去
We can get Carl there.
他们以为你们逃到了林子里
And they think all of you got away in the woods.
如今他们正在外面搜寻你们
They're out there, looking.
他们看见我们往西边去了
They saw us go West,
所以我们不能去西边
so we won't go West.
你们最明智的选择是待在这里
Your best chance is to stay here
等他们离开
until they're gone.
不
No.
如果他们找到了我们  我们就死定了
They find us here, we're dead.
他们就快消停了
They're almost done.
一定的
They gotta be.
他们的目标不是毁掉这个地方
It wasn't about destroying the place.
他们没有足够的弹药那么做
They don't have the ammo for that.
等风头过去
After they let up,
等他们离开之后
after they're gone,
我们就走
that's when we go.
好的
Okay.
我们等
We wait.
你确定去山顶寨是最好的选择吗
You sure going to Hilltop's the best plan?
你有更好的选择吗
You got a better one?
你们所有人  聚在同一个地方
All of you in one place, together...
我们所有人聚在一起...
All of us together...
将成为他们最可怕的噩梦
We'll be their worst damn nightmare.
假如我们要绕开他们
‭If we don't go through 'em,
那就必须穿过院子
we gotta go through the courtyard.
暴露在外
Exposed.
该动手了
This is it.
你想让我来吗
You want me to just do it?
不
No.
不  不
No. No.
全干掉
Got all of 'em.
不然他们有可能抓住亨利
They could've found Henry.
我知道
I know.
我担心的不是他们
I'm not worried about them.
走吧  小子们
Come on, boys.
别磨磨唧唧的
Get the damn gum off your shoes.
出发
Let's go!
会出乱子吗  以西结
Is it gonna go bad, Ezekiel?
会不会出什么岔子
Is this going to turn into something else?
你是今晚的编剧  加文
You are the author of this night, Gavin.
今晚的结局该和你创造的开头相称
Its close shall be fashioned by your start.
你走了
You left.
你应该在休息的
You were supposed to be resting.
我不累
I'm not tired.
是啊
Yeah.
你看上去光彩照人
You look great.
这一切必须停止  米琼恩
It's gotta stop, Michonne.
本来不应该是眼下这个情况的
It's not supposed to be like this.
我知道本来可以更好的
I know it can be better.
他们听着像是消停了
Sounds like they're letting up.
看来你说得对
Looks like you were right.
他们撤了
They're leaving.
也许吧
Maybe.
要我去看看吗
Want me to go take a look?
那里
There.
总比住在化工厂好
...sure as shit gonna beat living in that chemical dump.
你想要那间房
‭Hell, you want that room.
得和我打一架才行
you're gonna have to fight me for it...
别管了
Leave it.
走吧
Let's go.
给以西结留点空间
Leave some room for Ezekiel.
给他拿个枕头之类的
Get him a pillow or something.
这是他最后一程了
It's gonna be his last ride.
至少让他舒服点
Let's at least try to make him comfortable.
你努力  努力  不断努力
You try, and you try, and you try,
你期望  期望  不断期望
and you hope, and you hope, and you hope.
只希望一切最终能尘埃落定
Just wantin' things to finally just settle.
努力实现所谓该死的平衡
Achieve some goddamn, hard-fought equilibrium.
但是不
But, no.
永远会变成这样
It always comes down to this.
永远会变得黑暗  丑陋
It always has to get dark and ugly...
不人道
and inhuman.
你知道我不喜欢这样  对吗
You know I don't like this, right?
现在回头还来得及
It is not too late to walk back from something decided.
你回头了
You did,
看看你的下场
and look where it got you.
杜克  保利  你们在哪
Duke. Paulie. Where you at?
别折腾了  赶紧拿起对讲机回话
Stop pickin' dingles, grab your walkie, and respond!
戈麦斯
Gomez?
Gomez!
现在回头还来得及
It is not too late to walk back from something decided.
该死  来了
Shit. There it is.
把他带进去  快点
Get him inside. Now!
我调整了这些厨具
I calibrate this cooker properly,
我们想烤多少苹果就烤多少
we'll be lousy with baked apples ad infinitum.
我诚邀你当我的副厨
It would be my honor if you considered to be the sous to my chef.
或者我可以当副厨  你当主厨
Or I could be said sous, and you shall surely chef.
在那之前  这只黄苹果归你了
'Til then, this Golden Delicious has your name on it.
谢谢你  尤金
Thanks, Eugene.
谢谢
Thanks.
救世军走了
The Saviors are gone.
我们可以带大家去山顶寨
We can get everyone to Hilltop.
我们可以送卡尔去
We can get Carl there.
卡尔  不行
Carl? No.
达里尔可以搞一辆车
Daryl can get one of the cars.
卡尔撑不住...
Carl won't make --
他不能离开这里
He can't leave here.
-我得和他待在一起  -瑞克
- I have to stay with him. - Rick.
他撑不住
He can't.
我必须留下来
I have to stay.
那我们都留下来
We'll both stay.
你能...
Will you --
你能带朱迪斯走吗
Will you take Judith?
她得去那里
She needs to be there.
如果她...
If she...
如果...
If...
出事...
happens...
我带她去
I'll take her.
我带她去  我会保护好她
I'll get her there. I'll keep her safe.
交给我吧
I got this.
让我和她告别
Let me say goodbye.
你要乖乖的  好吗
You be good, okay?
为了米琼恩
For Michonne.
为了爸爸
For Dad.
你要尊重他
You gotta honor him.
他和你说话的时候得听话
Listen when he tells you stuff.
不用每次都听
You don't have to always.
有时候孩子得教爸妈怎么做
Sometimes, kids got to show their parents the way.
这帽子本来是我爸爸的
This was Dad's before it was mine.
现在是你的了
Now it's yours.
我说不好...
I don't know...Just --
有这帽子
Just having it and...
总让我感觉爸爸就在身边
It always kept Dad with me.
让我觉得自己和他一样强大
It made me feel as strong as him.
它帮了我许多
It helped me.
也许以后也能帮到你
Maybe it'll help you, too.
在妈妈死之前
Before Mom died...
她告诉我  我会战胜这个世界
...she told me that I was gonna beat this world.
我没做到
I didn't.
但你会做到的
But you will.
我知道你会的
I know you will.
过来
Here we go.
这些人
These people.
你救了他们所有人
You saved them all.
都是你的功劳
That's all you, man.
你帮我纪念我的母亲
You were helping me honor my mom...
不仅是你的
Not just yours.
还有我的母亲
Mine, too.
你带我来这里
You brought me here.
你给了我机会
You gave me a chance.
我知道我永远无法报答你
I know I can never repay you...
但我可以纪念你
but I can honor you
以行动  向你的队伍  朋友
by showing your people, your f-friends,
家人
your your family
证明你的牺牲没有白费
that what you did wasn't for nothing.
是有效果的
That it mattered.
是有意义的
That it... that it meant something.
因为确实有
Because it did.
这就是我要做的
So that's what I'm gonna do.
我会纪念你  卡尔
I'm gonna honor you, Carl.
恭喜
Congratulations.
你得与我们同行了
You're stuck with us.
好了
Okay.
他们没多少人  因为没剩下多少人了
There can't be a lot of 'em 'cause there aren't a lot left.
我们占领了屋子  入口难攻
We got room for us and controlled access.
大家堵住门  快
Force projected on the doors, now!
管它什么情况  我们都要解决
We end this, whatever the hell it is.
我必须收拾好这烂摊子  否则有棍棒之灾
I gotta settle this shit under the penalty of that goddamn bat.
你不必
You don't.
别再扯了  好吗
Shut up about that, okay?
现实如此  大势已去
This is it! It is too late.
我是编剧  你是死人
I'm the "Author," You're the dead man,
已成定局
and that's how it's gonna be.
你以为我还能变成别的角色吗
You think I can be someone else?
这就是我
This is who I am.
我活你死  这就是现实
I live, you die...this is what this is!
我为避免祸端做出的那些让步
The petty compromises I made to avoid conflict
都是以保全我的子民为名义
were always done in the name of saving my people's lives.
而我现在明白
Now I realize...
我只是在救你的命
I was saving yours.
到此为止
No more.
投降  不然我杀了他
Give up, or he's dead.
天啊
Jesus.
摩根  我们该走了
Morgan, ‭we should take our leave.
我们不用走
We don't need to go.
他们都死了
All of them are dead.
你还好吗
You okay?
我不希望我死后你悲伤
I don't want you to be sad after this.
-卡尔  -或者愤怒
- Carl... - ‭Or angry.
你必须坚强
You're gonna have to be strong.
为了我爸
For my dad.
为了朱迪斯
For Judith.
为了你自己
For yourself.
我会的
I will.
别背负这些
Don't carry this.
别背负这部分
Not this part.
你是我最好的朋友  米琼恩
You're my best friend, Michonne.
你也是我最好的朋友
You're mine, too.
你是我最好的朋友
You're mine.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
做什么
With what?
把他抬出去
Getting him out of here.
我们得停了
We need to stop.
前面有个房子  我们可以的
The house up ahead. We can make it.
没事的
It's okay.
没事的  把我放这就行
It's okay. Just put me down here.
没事的
It's okay.
-不  我们会走到的  -求你了
- No. We'll make it. - Please.
那里
There.
谢谢你们
Thanks...for...
带我走这么远
for getting me here.
对不起
I'm...I'm sorry.
我只是
I-I just...
不想让你在外面
I didn't...‭I didn't want you out there.
不是
‭No.
我是说  让我走到今天
No...for getting me here.
让我活到现在
For...for making it
让我成为...
so I could be who...
现在这样的人
who I wound up.
在监狱的时候
Back at the prison...
我们被袭击时
when we got attacked...
有个小孩
...there was a kid,
比我大一点
a little older than me.
他有一把枪
He had a gun.
他...
He was --
他正要放下枪
He was starting to put it down,
我...
and I-I s--
我开枪打了他
I shot him.
他正要投降
He was -- He was giving it up,
而我...
and I...I just...
我开枪打了他
I shot him.
我想到了他
I think about him.
我对他做的事
What I did to him
还有...
and how --
那么简单就杀了他
how easy it was to just...kill him.
你个疯子
You're sick!
只有疯子才会这样做
Only a sick man would do it like this.
你以为我想这样吗
You think I wanted this?
没别的选择
There wasn't a lot on the menu.
但我的小队很好
I ran a good crew.
我说话算话
I kept my word.
你去问以西结  我说话算话
You ask Ezekiel -- I kept my word!
你可以...
You -- You could --
你可以回山顶寨
You could go back to the Hilltop.
那里没沦陷
It's still standing.
他们被放了一马
They're keeping them going.
回头吧
Just turn around.
你以为你能打赢尼根吗
You think you can beat Negan?
你打不赢
You can't.
我们可以回到过去的状态
We can go back to how it was.
我们可以回到...
We can go back --
不
No.
卡尔  不
Carl, no.
不
No.
发生过的事
What happened...
你失去的东西
what you'd lost...
那些你不得不...
All those things you had to...
不得不做的事
All those thing you had to do...
你只是个...
You -- You -- You -- You were just --
你只是个孩子
You were just a boy.
你看到了
And you saw it.
那对我的影响
What it did.
杀人变得多么简单
How -- How easy it got.
你杀了这么多人  就为了那孩子吗
You just killed all those men because of the kid?!
杀了我不会让你释怀
Killing me won't make any of it go away.
你明早醒来依然会难受
You'll still wake up to the same shit tomorrow.
起来
Get up.
‭Up.
所以你变了
That's why you changed...
你接纳了伍德伯里的人
why you brought those people from Woodbury in...
你接纳了他们  我们住在了一起
You brought them in, and we all lived together.
我们曾是敌人
We were enemies.
你收起了枪
You put away your gun.
你那么做是为了让我改变
You did it so I could change,
是为了让我成为现在的我
so I could be who I am now.
你那时做的事
What you did then...
你停止了斗争
How you -- How you stopped fighting...
是对的
it was right.
依然是对的
It still is.
依然可以变成那样
It can be like that again.
你依然可以变成那样
You can still be like that again.
摩根
Morgan.
摩根  且慢
Morgan, cease this.
冷静
Relent.
杀他是懦夫之举
Ending him is the coward's way.
我们赢了
We've won.
没必要杀他
We don't have to kill him.
他会看到他的恶行
He will see what he has wrought,
那些都将成为他的负担
and all of it will be his to live with.
我不能变回以前的我
I can't be who I was.
现在不同了
It's different now.
你不能杀光他们  爸爸
‭You can't kill all of 'em, Dad.
未来一定有希望的
There's gotta be something after.
对你来说  对他们来说
For you...and for them.
未来一定有希望的
There's gotta be something after.
摩根  住手
Morgan, stop it.
你不想这样做  你不必这样做
You don't want to do this. You don't have to.
你告诉过我  我们能比他们更好
You told me we can be better than them.
这是你对我说的
You said that to me.
你不想这样做
You don't want to do this.
我知道  我能看出来
I know it. I can see it.
我...
I have --
我必须做
I have to.
我知道  你现在看不到
I know... you can't see it yet...
未来的样子
...how it could be.
但我看到了
But I have...
你蓄了胡
You have a beard.
更长
It's -- It's bigger...
更灰
and grayer...
米琼恩很幸福
Michonne's happy...
朱迪思长大了
Judith is older,
她在听我以前听过的歌
and she's listening to the songs that I used to before...
亚历山大扩张了
Alexandria's bigger.
有...
There's --
有新房子
There's new houses...
农作物
crops...
人们在工作
and people working.
每个人都在生活
Everybody living...
帮助其他人生活
helping everybody else live.
如果你能变回从前
If you can still be who you were...
未来就有可能变成那样
that's how it could be.
有可能的
It could.
卡尔
Carl.
全都是为了你
It was all for you.
从一开始就是
Right from the start.
在亚特兰大  农场
Back in Atlanta, the farm --
我所做的一切  都是为了你
everything I did, it was for you.
后来在监狱  是为了你和朱迪思
Then, at the prison, it was for you and Judith.
现在依然是  以后也会是
It still is. It's gonna be.
没什么能改变这点
And nothing -- ‭nothing is gonna change that.
我希望你拥有这样的未来  爸爸
I want this for you, Dad.
我会实现的  卡尔
I'm gonna make it real, Carl.
我发誓
I promise.
我会实现的
I'm gonna make it real.
亨利
Henry.
没关系
It's okay.
没事的
It's all right.
别看他  看我
Don't look at him. You look at me.
我必须做
I had to.
你应该留在小屋的
You were supposed to stay at the cottage.
你不该做这个
This wasn't what you were supposed to do.
-这不该你做  -卡萝尔
- This wasn't for you. ‭- Carol.
亨利
Henry.
一切自会解决
All will be resolved.
卡尔  对不起
Carl...I'm sorry.
我没能保护好你
I'm sorry I couldn't protect you.
父亲的责任是保护儿子
A father's job is to protect his son.
爱
Love.
责任只是爱
It's just to love.
不
No. No.
卡尔
Carl...
应该...
It -- It -- It...It should be --
我知道
I know. I know.
应该由你爱的人来
Somebody you love.
当你自己没法动手时
When you can't do it yourself.
但我依然能动手
But I still can.
我是大人了
I grew up.
我必须动手
I have to do this.
自己动手
Me.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我爱你  卡尔
I love you, Carl.
非常爱你
I love you so much.
我会实现的
I'll make it real.
我会的
I will.
早上好
Good morning.
早上好  亲爱的
Well, good morning to you, darlin'.